{
    "id": "04d670ea03b04d6993c98b4130b5b07d",
    "title": "Relative Pronoun Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "5ec36a2b5c244312b376b8b55ddce9eb",
            "title": "Relative Pronouns Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Get me the file ………………………… is on the table.",
                    "description": "Either which or that can be used in identifying relative clauses to refer to things.",
                    "answers": [
                        "that",
                        "which",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The house ………………………. she lived was very small.",
                    "description": "Where can mean in which.",
                    "answers": [
                        "where",
                        "which",
                        "that"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The boy …………………………. fell into the well was rescued.",
                    "description": "We use who to refer to people when the relative pronoun is the subject of the relative clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "who",
                        "whom",
                        "which"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The girl ………………………….. we met at the library is an aspiring writer.",
                    "description": "We use whom when the relative pronoun is the object of the relative clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "who",
                        "whom",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Ravi, ……………………….. is my nephew, is  a brilliant student.",
                    "description": "That cannot be used in non-identifying relative clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "who",
                        "that",
                        "whom"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is the dog ………………………… I was talking about.",
                    "description": "Either that or which can refer to animals in identifying relative clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "that",
                        "which",
                        "what"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The exhibition ………………………….. was held in the town hall attracted tens of thousands of people.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "which",
                        "what",
                        "who"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where are the books ………………………. I left on the table?",
                    "description": "Either that or which can refer to things in identifying relative clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "that",
                        "which",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The man ………………………… car was stolen went to the police.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "who",
                        "who's",
                        "whose"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I know a girl …………………………. brother serves in the army.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "who",
                        "who's",
                        "whose"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The rope ………………………… was old snapped.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "which",
                        "what",
                        "who"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}